Dipesh Pandey

Backend Developer

Info

pandey.dipesh50@gmail.com +47 4862 4918

Oslo, Norway / Remote

LinkedIn >

Github >

Website >

Working Languages

English (professional)
Norwegian (basic)

References

Available upon request

Bio

I am a backend developer with over three years of experience in coding. My top skills are Python (Django, Flask), Javascript, and SQL. I have worked in a few industries at junior levels including martech, event-tech, and crypto. In the last few years, I have focused on sharpening my skills in building cloud-native platforms while looking to work for companies that value flexibility and high-quality software.

Top skills

Programming Languages
Front End Development
Back End Development
Databases
Cloud Platforms
Dev Ops

Python, Javascript, Go Angular Django, Flask, Node.js, Nest.js SQL, PostgreSQL AWS, GCP Docker

Projects

Developer (Contract) | Haifix

2021 - 2022

I worked as the sole developer to ship a product for forex traders. It is a CMS platform to manage trades and earnings of users. Right now, it is in the phase of marketing and acquiring customers.

Tech: Python, Django, Javascript, HTML

Developer (Contract) | ProofPit

2021-2022

I was involved in a public project that involved building a SaaS platform for crypto traders, especially in Austria and Germany. The platform would be able to aggregate trading portfolios for the users and provide them an idea about taxation and profits for the fiscal year. I handled the backend development of the project collaborating with a few other developers. Tech: Python, Django, GCP, Redis

Developer | CrunchEvent

2020 - 2021

Crunchevent is my personal project where the idea is to build an event

management platform that maximizes the in-person experience. Using many interactive components for the participants, this platform aims to handle the onboarding, during-event, as well as post-event components for the organizers. I worked as a frontend developer with two other friends and currently working on getting the beta version of the product.

Tech: Angular, Typescript, Firebase, Javascript, HTML

Work Experience

Freelance Developer (Part-Time/Remote) | Teamcoda

2018 - 2020

I worked in a team of professional freelancers from the Netherlands to help clients build their MVPs. I worked as a backend developer with some frontend work, especially focused on API development, web crawling, and SPA development.

Tech: Python, Flask, NestJS, Angular, Agile

Software Developer (Remote) | MyriadX

2018 - 2020

I worked as a junior developer after finishing my bachelors from Nepal while communicating with the core team in Singapore. The tasks would be to contribute to the backend and APIs of the company's core product as well as some data analysis tasks. I was the first hire of the Nepal team, and later I helped grow the team upto 6.

Tech: Python, Angular, AWS, Firebase, SQL, Agile

Education & Courses

Master of Applied Computer Science / Norwegian University of Science and Technology (NTNU) | <u>Thesis ></u> 2020-2022

The masters focused on analyzing the Ethereum blockchain, especially Uniswap, to identify the trends and patterns on how token pairs are traded and understand how decentralized these exchange platforms are.